what happened to Apple Vision Pro in the
six months since I bought mine The
Narrative around this product has
changed drastically from Apple's
Visionary new product is the most
technologically advanced ever to the
Apple Vision Pro is a dud flop and a
miss but why what the hell happened in
the course of 6 months to justify that
change is the Vision Pro actually a flop
and would I recommend buying one first
let me take you through what I've
actually been using mine for the first
big thing I've been using the Vision Pro
for is for novelty experiences the
dinosaur encounter is the best example
of this oh it's looking right at me holy
sh
holy I knew it was going to do this that
your walls open up into the Jurassic age
and a giant dinosaur looks right at you
as it steps through your living room
other apps like Kung Fu Panda's
meditation lessons and Disney Marvel's
what if offers similar experiences what
makes these experiences so novel and
compelling is how the Vision Pro can
make you feel like the characters and
creatures you're seeing can also see you
well yes other headsets like the quest 3
offer similar experiences The Vision Pro
sells this illusion of presence way more
thanks to its better displays graphics
and performance another immersive
experience can transport you to Mount
Hood or the surface surf of the Moon in
what Apple calls environments these are
mainly places in the real world that
have been recreated to make it feel like
you're right there though some apps like
Disney plus and Max have created their
own like the throne room from Game of
Thrones the purpose of these
environments is to help block out
everything around you so you can focus
on completing a certain task or you just
want to have a space to have a giant
screen to watch something on meditating
in these environments can also be fun
Apple's updated meditation app for The
Vision Pro has this very soothing 3D
breathing guide now one of the best
parts of Oni A Vision Pro is watching
other people try it on Via guest mode
it's hilarious seeing other people react
to the dinosaur coming right at them but
again that's novelty it's the thing that
gets you excited about a product and
then perhaps buy it but it's rarely the
thing that actually keeps you using it
over the long term and that leads me to
the vision Pro's next big feature which
is Apple immersive video Apple immersive
video is a new format that makes you
feel like you've been put right in the
middle of a 180° IMAX movie the people
and animals you see feel real I just
couldn't stop smiling watching this mini
do about a rhino Sanctuary especially in
the shot where it just looks like the
rhinos are right in front of you and you
could just Reach Out And Touch them it
sells the illusion that well and through
an apple immersive video trailer apple
is actually shown off what live sports
footage can look like in this format and
it is also just insane like it makes you
feel like you're sitting courtside at a
Lakers game or you're on the sidelines
during the Super Bowl it is by far the
most compelling Sports viewing
experience I've ever experienced outside
of actually being at the game to me it's
one of the most compelling things about
Vision Pro and there's more content
coming to The Vision Pro including the
first ever scripted show in this format
from Oscar winning director Edward
burger and speaking of content the last
main thing I've been using the Vision
Pro for is watching 2D movies and TV
shows unless you have a giant theater in
your home nothing else will come close
to the experience of watching content on
Vision Pro this headset is the same to
TVs and movie theaters as what the
airpods are to stereo systems and
speakers and yes you can watch 3D movies
as well though I've mainly stuck to 2D
movies as some 3D movies with a screen
as large as what you get in the Vision
Pro I've noticed it can cause me to get
a bit motion sick now while I don't use
the Vision Pro as much as my TV there
are two main use cases where I found I
prefer it to watch content on one is
when I'm traveling and I don't have a
great TV setup like when I was at the
beach and I wanted to watch the latest
episode of House of dragon I've also
found it useful for when I want to watch
TV during the day where unlike my TV
there there's no glare from surrounding
Windows the sound quality of the vision
Pro's dual driver audio pods is actually
pretty good I didn't immediately feel
the need to reach for my earbuds when I
was watching something however using a
set of Apple's newest version of airpods
Pro with the USBC case those do
significantly improve the audio
experience of the Vision Pro by blocking
out background noise and providing way
better bass so what have I not used the
Vision Pro 4 first is using it for work
you can use it with a Mac to create a
giant virtual Mac window which is great
for when you're working off a Macbook or
MacBook Air and want to view content on
a larger screen the second work use case
is having a bunch of apps in multiple
virtual Windows around you but I find
that use case less compelling it looks
cool and it does allow you to Conta
switched faster meaning you can move
from one task to another and then back
to the other task but that context
switching is more mentally taxing I do
like that I can just move a window
completely out of view to focus on
another window though now would I use
Vision Pro to replace my studio display
no using the studio display as my
monitor is just more comfortable
depending on the person and the
situation I can see a use case for when
you're traveling without a monitor and
using the Vision Pro with your MacBook
for quick spurts when you want a larger
display the environments can be nice to
work in because they help block out all
the distractions around you it's like
noise cancellation for your vision
though I'm not sure I'd have the courage
to wear it in a coffee shop just yet
gaming is another thing I haven't found
myself using the Vision Pro 4 I've tried
a few and looked at plenty of games out
there for it but they're either too
expensive for me to want to really try
them out or they just haven't really
appealed to me though I'm the type of
gamer that plays very few games but of
the games I do play i s a lot of hours
into them so this might just be a me
thing FaceTime is another feature I
haven't used I've used it once to scare
my family members with my Persona which
The Vision Pro creates when it scans
your face during initial setup the last
thing I haven't found myself using
Vision Pro for at all is specifically
for airline travel mainly because of its
size if you're already bringing a
carryon bag and a personal item onto a
plane The Vision Pro in its case is
going to take up a lot of space in one
of those bags though yes you could just
take the Vision Pro like this and put it
directly into one of your bags though
given how much this device costs and how
fragile some of its components are I'm
not sure I'd recommend doing that so if
the Vision Pro can do some pretty
incredible things why did it fade so
quickly and why do people consider it a
flop do I consider it a flop no not
necessarily it depends on how you look
at the Vision Pro Pro its underlying
technology platform and the product
itself when looking at the underlying
technology platform I think Apple
actually did what they set out to do the
highresolution micro OLED panels that's
the tech responsible for creating such a
crisp image with outstanding color
reproduction and contrast they also move
the Vision Pro will actually scan the
distance between your eyes to align the
displays perfectly for that 3D depth
effect which is key to viewing
everything in the Vision Pro like
spatial photos and videos while the
spatial photos and videos captured on my
iPhone 15 Pro Max aren't nearly as
impressive as the ones captured on the
Vision Pro itself thanks to the better
depth effect it creates even today I
think spatial photos and videos are
compelling though somewhat limiting
since better videos can only be taken
with Vision Pro and overall their
resolution and Clarity isn't as crystal
clear as you want it to be hopefully
that'll improve over time oddly enough
for me today panoramas are the most
impressive photo video feature on Vision
Pro because it can recreate the
perspective you had when you took the
Panorama and its high res so it looks
really impressive the lidar and Camera
Suite is another incredible technology
packed into Vision Pro it's the reason
the tracking and placement of virtual
objects in your environment feels so
damn real the camera Suite also helps
power Apple's hand and eye tracking
which is actually quite good it allows
you to look at something with your eyes
and pinch your fingers together to
select it though parts of the experience
over the past 6 months have still felt a
bit clunky like when watching Apple
immersive videos often when you glance
up the little dot for the control center
constantly appears with its default
setting though Apple has addressed this
with a new hand gesture in Vision OS 2
which comes out later this year here and
sometimes I find the eye tracking to be
a bit fatiguing honestly when you're
always having to look at the thing
you're trying to select and then
sometimes you like look at the wrong
thing you select the wrong thing and
yeah now the last major Hardware
breakthrough with Vision Pro is the R1
chip to make the eye and hand tracking
as well as object placement work so
quickly that you can't perceive any lag
Apple had to design a chip separate from
the normal processor to run all of those
tasks now now does the R1 chip mean you
can't get any motion sickness while
wearing Vision Pro no but it does
significantly reduce the chances of that
happening I've only noticed getting
motion sick when watching a 3D movie
occasionally when walking around with a
headset on and my eyes are dry or in a
situation where the tracking goes
berserk like when my Apple TV screen
saver turned on in a dimly lit room and
the headset decided to track against
that overall Vision Pro's underlying
technology ol is insanely impressive but
where the Vision Pro will likely feel
like a flop to some is all of the issues
with the product experience the weight
of the device is the most glaring issue
Apple Vision Pro can weigh 600 to 650 g
depending on the light seal and headband
configuration and that's just too damn
heavy for most people worse is Apple
shipped to pretty garbage headbands for
Distributing the weight of the Vision
Pro around around your head the first is
the solo nit band which has an awesome
adjustable dial and great fabric
material however Apple decided not to
ship it with the optional head strap
which they originally showed off at WWDC
they instead shipped the solo knit band
with the additional dual Loop band the
problem is the Dual Loop band is harder
to adjust and the bottom strap doesn't
cover as much of your head as the solo
knit band does for weight distribution
wearing the Vision Pro with the solo
knit band without any additional type of
head strap over top that's typically
going to cause the Vision Pro to dig
into your cheeks or your forehead as you
continue to wear it to remedy that
you'll either try to move it or further
tighten it and it's easy to overtighten
it to the point where it can cause
headaches migraines and general Facial
Pain wearing Vision Pro gave me the
first migraine I've ever experienced in
my entire life and it got so bad that I
just really regretted buying a Vision
Pro but thankfully a third party
accessory maker came to my rescue I
bought this speeden Vision Pro headstrap
which is a similar design to what Apple
originally showed off with the solo nit
band and should have shipped even with
this strap and they're not a sponsor by
the way even with the strap The Vision
Pro it does still feel heavy yes but
it's not unmanageable since getting it
I've been able to comfortably wear
Vision Pro for well over an hour with no
Facial Pain or headaches afterward I've
left a link to it and the other
accessories for Vision Pro in the blog
post for this review at 6months l.net
link to that in the description below
now there is one more Comfort problem
though that Still Remains for me with
Vision Pro and that's eye strain and eye
fatigue because we all tend to Blink
less when we look at displays and
screens our eyes will then dry out feel
more strained and fatigued which is why
you've probably heard of the 202020 rule
where every 20 minutes you're supposed
to look at something 20 ft away for at
least 20 seconds well that's kind of
hard to do in The Vision Pro if you're
watching a movie it's not really
practical now I've noticed this is worse
when wearing contacts versus glasses
with headsets like Vision Pro if you do
wear contacts one thing I found that's
really helped me after a long session
with Vision Pro is getting some eye
drops like these and just putting a few
drops in each eye to help refreshen them
and cause them not to be as dry now what
about battery life 2 hours sounds like
not that much but when you take the ey
strain plus the weight of the device
into account to me the battery life has
actually been pretty adequate and if you
want to use Vision Pro longer you always
have the option to plug it in now
another reason why people might feel
like The Vision Pro is a flop is app
availability most of the apps just
provide novelty but again novelty can
only get you so far I just haven't
really found anything that's kept me
wanting to come back and use the headset
outside of core content apps like the
max app but the content app availability
is lacking 6 months in there's not an
official Netflix or YouTube app now one
reason developers of larger apps might
have been more hesitant to develop for
the Vision Pro is Apple's business model
for it the company has called Vision Pro
its first spatial computer I don't know
about you but when I hear the word
computer I typically think of file
systems open protocols oh and the
ability to download software freely
outside of Apple's App Store wal Garden
The Vision Pro isn't that it's more like
a spatial iPad and I think the software
development for this device has suffered
because of that the last thing about the
Vision Pro that I think contributes to
this feeling like this product is a flop
is Apple just over engineered it
eyesight is a good example of this it
makes it sort of look like you can see
the person's eyes as they look at you
while wearing Vision Pro but in in
reality from most angles it looks kind
of goofy oddly when looking at yourself
in the mirror though it looks pretty
decent Motions like when you blink your
eyes happen pretty much in real time
which is impressive now in order to get
eyesight to work Apple needed to create
a 3D scan of your face which is your
Apple Persona now how well my facial
movements here map to my Persona and
blinking the eyes everything that is
impressive but the end result is still a
little bit uh yikes Vision Pro's fit is
also complex Apple made like 30s
something different light seals for it
depending on which light seal you're
fitted with the field of view or the
amount of virtual space that you see
when you put the Vision Pro on can
actually decrease luckily I was fitted
with the 21w seal which has a decent
field of view another complication with
the Vision Pro Design is you can't wear
glasses while wearing the headset you'll
need to upload your prescription and
Order Zeiss Optical inserts which
magnetically pop into the Vision Pro and
cost anywhere from 100 to
$150 another downside with Vision Pro is
there's no multi-user support if you
live with somebody else that also wants
to use this on occasion every time they
want to use it they have to use guest
mode which means they have to reset up
their hand and eye tracking every single
time they use the headset there's also a
Content DRM that basically prevents you
from doing any screen recordings while
watching any movies or TV shows which
makes sharing how great the movie
watching experience is on social pretty
difficult you can also see Reflections
and some minimal glare towards the
bottom of the lens when viewing content
which some might find to be a
downside so do I recommend getting an
apple Vision Pro for almost everyone out
there the answer to that question is no
novelty will only entertain for so long
and
$3,500 is a lot to spend on novelty plus
a giant virtual TV and computer monitor
even for the use cases I use it for
you're probably better off getting a 75
or heck even an 83 in OLED television
and you'd still spend less than
$3500 and you could watch content with
other people but what if it wasn't
$3,500 what if it was $1,500
at that price I might very well
recommend it depending on what
trade-offs Apple made to get it down to
that price the TV watching and apple
immersive video format are compelling if
they could somehow keep the excellent
displays make the device lighter I think
it would be a better product so overall
yes I have found a use for the Vision
Pro that does keep me coming back to the
headset time and time again I don't
think the device is a total flop the
technology platform Apple developed is
seriously impressive but I don't
recommend getting the device because too
many of the products downsides outweigh
its highlights it's a device that feels
like something from the future but is
hampered by the present form factor
business model and extra features Apple
decided to go
with if you want to learn even more
about the Vision Pro and how it compares
to the much cheaper meta Quest 3 as well
as my full six months later review of
The Meta quest Quest 3 you can get to
those videos by clicking here and to see
more of my Apple reviews you can get to
those by clicking the playlist here or
by simply following us at 6months
l.net if you like this video and found
it helpful make sure you hit that Thumbs
Up Button below and subscribe to the
channel for more for 6 months later I'm
Josh tedar thanks for watching