[Music]
introducing Apple Vision
Pro the era of spatial
Computing is
[Music]
here when you put on Apple Vision Pro
you see your world and everything in it
your favorite apps live right in front
of you but now they're in your
space this is Vision OS Apple's first
ever spatial operating
system it's familiar yet
groundbreaking you navigate with your
eyes simply tap to select flick to
scroll s and use your voice to
dictate it's like
magic apps
Dimension react to
light and cast
Shadows even though these spatial
experiences are happening inside Vision
Pro it looks sounds and feels like they
are physically
there foundational to Apple Vision Pro
is that you're not isolated from other
people when someone else is in the room
you can see them and they can see you to
talk to me about sushi sushi all right
see you take
care because you're not limited by a
display apps live in your
space your photos can be life-size or
any size so your living room becomes a
gallery and panoramas wrap around you as
if you're right where you took
[Music]
them Apple Vision Pro is Apple's first
ever 3D
camera now you can capture photos and
videos with remarkable depth and relive
a memory as if you're right back in the
exact
[Music]
moment hey
Dad experiences on Vision Pro can also
expand in three dimensions filling the
entirety of your space
like in the mindfulness app where you
can create a moment of
[Music]
calm Apple Vision Pro brings the scale
and wonder of a movie theater to
whatever space you're in it
automatically darkens and casts a
beautiful glow into the
room and you can make the screen as big
as you want and spatial audio surrounds
you and makes you feel like you're a
part of the
action and for an extraordinary
cinematic
experience you can bring in a beautiful
environment and make your screen feel
100 ft
[Music]
wide now here to start Vision Pro is a
wonderful way to play your favorite
games Curry against just connect your
controller
and play on a massive screen with
Incredible
[Applause]
audio with apple Vision Pro you can
create the perfect workspace no matter
where you
are the web comes to life at Fantastic
scale text is crisp and easy to
read browsing the internet feels
new and Safari expands so you can see
all your open
[Music]
tabs your favorite apps from Apple and
the App Store are
there you can arrange them however you
like and work seamlessly across
them hi hey hi did you receive the deck
yeah I'm looking at it now oh great you
got so what did you think FaceTime looks
and sounds amazing in apple Vision Pro
youu people life siize and with spatial
audio you hear them as if they're right
in front of you so conversation is more
natural and collaborating becomes even
easier and because you see the world
around you you can glance at a
notification and even connect your Mac
simply by looking at it turning a 13-in
screen into a giant display
in apple Vision Pro you can also
transform your space with environments
like on a plane you can now watch a
movie on a huge screen in a stunning
location and you control just how
immersed you want to be
[Music]
to make all these digital experiences
feel real in your space takes an
extraordinary amount of Technology yet
Apple Vision Pro is remarkably Compact
and beautiful a single piece of
three-dimensionally formed laminated
glass acts as a lens through which the
cameras and sensors view the world it
flows seamlessly into a lightweight
aluminum alloy frame that gently curves
to wrap around your face and we designed
a modular system so you can find the
right
fit the light seal keeps stray light
from your eyes and a soft frame gently
flexes and conforms to your unique
features the headband is 3D knitted to
provide cushioning breathability and
stretch and a high performance battery
reduces weight to a minimum and slips
easily into your
pocket because you wear Apple Vision Pro
and your eyes are covered we engineered
A system that uses Advanced machine
learning to represent you realistically
when you're in FaceTime your persona
dynamically reflects your face and head
movements well so when you're
chatting people see your eyes hands and
true expressions
to convincingly Place content in your
space took thousands of groundbreaking
Innovations and custom
Technologies since your eyes see the
world with Incredible resolution we
built a micro OLED display system that
fits 64 pixels in the same amount of
space as a single iPhone pixel and packs
23 million into two panels the size of a
postage
stamp that's more than a 4K TV for each
eye giving you jaw-dropping lifelike
Clarity Apple Vision Pro also features
our most advanced spatial audio system
ever personalized sound is delivered
directionally to your ear and audio Ray
tracing uses sophisticated sensors to
understand the materials and objects in
your room so sound feels like it's
coming from the world around
you 3D mapping provides a detailed
understanding of Walls Furniture and
even people so all experiences look
sound and feel like they are physically
there to power a spatial computer like
apple Vision Pro required an Innovative
dual chip design M2 provides phenomenal
performance and a brand new chip R1
processes sensor data at incredible
speed virtually eliminating lag so
experiences take place in real time
right in front of your
eyes dely great inside a stunning new
way to use the apps we
love a powerful way to relive our
memories a profound new way to be
together thank you so much and a magical
way to be immersed in
entertainment the era of spatial
Computing is
here this is Apple Vision Pro