a year ago Apple released the Apple
Vision Pro their first spatial Computing
headset and for the first week it really
seemed like everyone excitedly went out
to buy a $3500 headset until 2 weeks
later when the content all dried up
because everyone who bought one returned
it but you know what I didn't so here's
what it's like using the Apple Vision
Pro one year later from someone who
didn't return the Apple Vision Pro is it
any better well let's talk about it okay
so to understand where it is today we
have to do a little bit of a
retrospective first why did everyone
find this thing so cool in the first
place well with every Apple product
launch there's some slick marketing and
hype maybe a little too much hype for a
product that seemed to have been rumored
forever VR and AR experiences are some
of the coolest things that you can try
for the first time for about 15 minutes
until the novelty wears off and you look
yourself in the mirror and realize just
how you look but honestly the Apple
Vision Pro is definitely a vision or
glimpse into the future of what good AR
and VR could be the you Y and resolution
is crisp and using just your hands
instead of a physical controller
genuinely does feel like the future you
can enjoy working in 3D spaces with
Windows and displays everywhere or you
can immerse yourself in a film with a
giant display right in front of you and
while there are limited games the games
that do work you can run them pretty
decently it's absolutely insane that all
of this could be done with today's Tech
in a device like this and for that
purpose it just can't be beat but
there's also many many different reasons
why it didn't stick for for regular
people first is price and the value that
you get for that price what it does
better than just owning a regular Mac
and a different VR headset is outshined
by just how much cheaper those things
are at doing those tasks and where the
Vision Pro excels and does things better
than any computer or VR headset can even
do doesn't justify paying that crazy
price tag don't get me wrong it's
fantastic and impressive every single
time you put the Vision Pro on nothing
comes close to it but it's an experience
that I don't think everyone deems is
worth 32 Grand there hasn't been a
single discount since it's been released
either then there's also how difficult
it is to show people visually how the
Apple Vision Pro Works Apple initially
released it in the US before expanding
to a couple more countries but at least
here in the US the only retailer that
sells the Apple Vision Pro is Apple so
it's not easy to just walk into your
local electronic store and try it out
and see if you like it you have to go
specifically to an Apple store which
there are way less of just to try it or
order it online line and I don't know
about you if I don't know much about a
product I'm not quick to drop 3 and2
Grand on something unseen and it doesn't
help that even in YouTube videos it's a
pain trying to show what using the
experience is like on camera since you
typically just get a standard 4K 2D
video of how it looks versus the entire
immersive view that you would with the
headset on like this video doesn't do it
justice then there's the device itself
it's nice to touch in the hand has lots
of Glass and Metal it's very premium
built but it's heavy it's hard to wear
comfortably for long periods of time and
takes up a ton of space in your backpack
so it's super inconvenient to use when
traveling making that private movie
viewing experience a huge hassle to Lug
around with you through airports I mean
you can fit like three pairs of clothes
in the space that A Vision Pro takes up
in a bag some people have issues with
the look but honestly I don't think
that's a major issue at all I mean they
are a bit strange but everyone made fun
of airpods when they came out calling
them toothbrush heads but after a few
years they were everywhere also because
these things are so expensive and so few
people have them using them is a very
lonely and isolating experience both as
an owner and the fact that when you're
using it it feels disconnected from the
physical world with very few ways to
share what you're experiencing and in
full immersion and lastly the biggest
issue with the Vision Pro at release was
that the app library and features were
just not enticing there just weren't
that many apps made specifically for the
Vision Pro I mean it did have iPad app
support but that was also pretty Limited
at launch the main issues were the high
price tag the barrier to actually use it
in action or try it the lack of great
apps and software and the overall
comfort of the device which all led to
an impressive device that doesn't feel
ready for Mass Appeal but okay Jimmy
that was all last year at release a lot
of things can change in 365 days but
does it change whether anyone should get
an Apple Vision Pro today well first the
device itself is a lot better Apple has
dropped new software updates that
probably should have been there from the
beginning like more screen real estate
when you mirror your Mac display new
gesture controls that make it easier to
access everything from your fingertips
instead of looking up to pull in the
control center and finally a better
guest mode that saves the previous guest
so that they don't have to go through
the annoying setup and the OS itself
does feel a bit more stable than it did
at launch all these software tweaks are
nice additions and make the Vision Pro
feel more complete and cohesive within
the Apple ecosystem but again it feels
like these features should have been
here in the first place but it still
does make the Vision Pro nicer to use
especially the giant ultrawide Mac
virtual display it just came way too
late I find that a good informal Health
indicator of how popular a tech product
is and how people use their device is
the third party accessory markets for it
all big electronic purchases whether
that's a laptop tablet smartphone game
console or even a camera have
accessories and you know once you get
your shiny new electronics you're
already planning some accessory
purchases for it so just a quick glance
on Apple's website and Amazon shows you
two things one how few accessories there
are for the Vision Pro and two how few
people are actually buying these
accessories it doesn't seem like the
Apple Vision Pro is all that popular at
least from an accessory standpoint and
even when looking at Google trends for
the Apple Vision Pro it seems like the
overall hype for this device is just
straight up dead so while the software
is a lot better A year later the
accessories market for the Vision Pro
and how many people people actually have
purchased this Vision Pro seems tiny
especially by Apple product standards so
the Apple Vision Pro has gotten better
over the last year even if sales are
sluggish but they don't live in a vacuum
there are other companies that are
working on better and better headsets as
well Samsung has their project muhan
headset that looks a little too similar
to the Apple Vision Pro it could
potentially be really interesting and
might be a solid alternative or you
could look at what's available on the
market today like meta Quest 3s which is
already a compelling headset which by
the way this thing costs 10 times less
than the Apple Vision Pro one thing I
want to make 100% clear is that this
thing is not a competitor to division
Pro so the comparisons are a little
unfair there if you're comparing what
type of things you can accomplish with
both device but what this does do is
give us an idea of how cheap VR and AR
headsets can get as well as how good
they can be at this price point what
regular everyday people can afford The
Vision Pro like inside is technically so
impressive it's got plenty of power
thanks to that M2 Chip and the displays
are beautiful it just doesn't have
enough going for it to justify that
large price tag while the meta Quest 3s
nothing about this device screams
premium but it's comfortable to wear has
the option to use controllers or finger
gestures to navigate the device and it's
cheap okay I hate making up random
numbers to describe my personal
experience but the Vision Pro experience
feels about three times better than the
meta Quest 3s now does it justify it
being 10 times more expensive for that
three times better experience no but
that's kind of like comparing a $300 TV
you see in a store to a $3,000 premium
OLED TV they both do the job but the
comparisons just aren't Fair could you
argue that a fancy money shredding OLED
TV does a job 10 times better than that
budget brand no but it's the latest and
greatest flagship and you're paying a
premium to be cutting edge that's kind
of what the Vision Pro is right now but
what will be interesting at least to me
is out of these two or any other
competitors that enter the market who
can reach that sweet sweet Middle Ground
first where you get nice premium
features that you see in the Vision Pro
today at a reasonable price that's when
I think these VR AR XR whatever you want
to call them spatial Computing devices
would be really interesting all right so
what's next for the Apple Vision Pro
well I think that Apple's just going to
look forward and try this path a little
bit longer there's rumors that
production ended for the Vision Pro in
late 2024 due to lower than expected
sales but that's not the end into
Apple's attempt into these type of
devices because apple is rumored to
release a more budget friendly version
sometime in the near future so in the
meantime they really should be
continuing to flesh out the features of
the Vision Pro so that when this new
cheaper model releases it'll hit the
ground running with a more thought out
OS hopefully you get some great apps
because it's still pretty Barren and is
mostly suited for consuming streamed
content there's also rumors that apple
and Sony are working together to support
PlayStation VR2 controllers with the
Vision Pro which could help it function
better as both a gaming machine because
the M series processors in there are
already pretty good at that and to just
navigate with VR controls because doing
everything with hand gestures for an
extended period of time kind of just
drains you so was the hype around the
Apple Vision Pro unwarranted sort of
there's a reason why people were so
interested in this product it was and
still is a really interesting piece of
technology like this proves that it can
be done with the tech that we have today
but it also shows us how far away we are
from this actually being useful to the
average person it'll be years before
this type of Technology becomes small
enough comfortable enough powerful
enough and cheap enough to actually be
accessible to everyone because let's be
real if this thing was like $1,500
comfortable to wear for long periods of
time less bulky and had a much more
robust app ecosystem this thing would
sell a lot better but until then
headsets like the Apple Vision Pro will
probably remain pretty Niche for a while
but hopefully a device like this spurred
up the competition a bit so that we as
consumers get way more competition maybe
meta will make a successor to The Meta
Quest Pro or Samsung makes a retail
version of their project muhan headset
who knows either way this isn't the
first time that we've seen an AR VR XR
spatial Computing headset it won't be
the last time we see something like this
either so for me personally today in
February
2025 would I rather own this or save
$3,500 I'd rather save $3500 anyway what
do you personally think did you consider
the Apple Vision Pro has your opinion on
it changed honestly I had some hope for
it but it feels largely the same a year
later despite some of the main software
updates the app ecosystems just still
isn't there for me leave all that down
in the comment section below and I'll
see you all next time bye